A thousand years ago they saved Howlem by sacrificing themselves.
But nothing disappears completely, they are still here in the Tree...
They were with their people, saw their joys and troubles...
It is enough just to call... They will respond, I can feel it...
You were fast as lightning, but now you are fast asleep, Val. I'm sorry.
You have seen the peaks of the highest mountains, but eternal dreams have seized you, Orn. I'm sorry.
I feel... a living Thread calling for help...
It beats like a heart... But we need more power, otherwise I won’t be able to pull it out.
Yes, I see the outlines, as though through a fog... But more power is needed.
Yes, it's a squirrel - I see the silhouette now. It's sleeping. I need more power to wake it up.
It… woke up. Ratatoskr! The squirrel that jumps between the branches of the Great Ash Tree.
We can speak with the goddess! I can sense that the Tree has its own mind and its thoughts are linked with hers. But it won't be easy...